now that you have seen what data
dependencies look like let's do a data
dependencies quiz to see if you can find
data dependencies in the program let's
say that these are 4 instructions in our
program instruction 1 multiplies R 2 and
R 3 puts the result in R 1 instruction
to takes R 4 and R 1 add them up and put
the result in R for instruction 3
multiplies r5 and r6 puts the result in
r1 and the subtract here instruction 4
subtracts r1 from R 4 and puts the
result back in our for you need to
indicate whether there are any
dependencies between instruction i1 and
i2 for each of these three types of
dependencies is there such a dependence
you need to do that also for I 1 2 I 3 I
1 to I for so is there a dependence from
i1 to i4 and from I 2 to i3 to help you
out I'm gonna tell you that there is a
read after write dependence here that
there is no write after read dependence
from i1 to i2 and that there is no write
after write dependence I'm also gonna
tell you that there is no read after
write dependence here but you need to
figure out the remaining 8 dependencies
put a checkmark in each of these boxes
if there is such a dependence between
these instructions